DILVA E. MANZO

11720 SW Gaarde St-Tigard, OR 97224

503-550-7507 dilya.manzo@gmail.com

Highly motivated, with experience in market research, analytical tools, market trends, and competitor activity. Ability to create relevant, timely, and concise analysis and documentation of market trends and emerging business issues that impact the company's business lines. Organized, detail oriented and team player that is highly driven to success. Ability to interact with multiple projects simultaneously. Knowledge in the railroad industry trends.

Professional Experience

Marketing Associate - The Greenbrier Companies, Lake Oswego, OR - Mar, 2006 - Present

Collaborated with the VP of Marketing and Sales to enhance and create marketing materials. Composed and maintained market size data statistics. Created competitive analysis matrices and collaborated on keeping statistics of competitor activity. Composed a variety of marketing sales presentations for key customers. Attended educational conferences to stay current with industry trends and to establish and cultivated relationships with customers. Collaborated in the development of plans that would promote overall success and growth for the company, such as assisting with multi-year plans, forecasting reports, marketing analysis of industry equipment and commodities. Reported on key economic indicators on a monthly basis and distributed industry news internally on a daily basis.

Accounts Payable Analyst - The Greenbrier Companies, Lake Oswego, OR - May 2004 - Mar, 2006

Developed desk procedures for department and formatted as needed. Prepared batch invoices for data entry and processed vendor invoices for payment. Responded to inquiries on historical and current status of invoices. Processed employee expense reports and scanned all documents/receipts needed to be documented.

Insurance Agent/Office Manager - Allstate Insurance, Hood River, OR - Jan, 1999 - May 2004

Selling and sales servicing casualty insurance policies. Soliciting new clients by marketing and networking through participation in community events and local clubs. Created large Hispanic customer base and taught the Hispanic portion of driver education. Follow-up with policy renewals and problem solving for clients in times of need with accidents and personal losses. Responsible for the overall operation of daily office functions and duties requiring the advanced knowledge of company policies and practices. Responsible for the staffing and training of the office.

Additional Skills

Proficient in MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Paint.Net, and Adobe Knowledge of Salesforce.com and SharePoint Bilingual – Spanish Strong verbal and written communication Experience in developing and maintaining client relations

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Marketing and Management – Portland State University, Portland, Oregon – 2005 International Studies Certificate – Portland State University, Portland, Oregon – 2005